Johan B Hennius Junior Full-Stack Developer

Cardiff

johanbhennius@outlook.com | 07825279251

Github | LinkedIn | Portfolio

Adaptable and enthusiastic Junior Full-Stack Developer from a professional creative studio background. Outcome-focused and experienced in working as part of a team while liaising with clients to ensure that each project surpasses expectations and adheres to budgets and deadlines. Extensive knowledge of the design process and great attention to detail with ability to think creatively and solve problems. Desire to utilise skills to as part of an inspiring team where I can develop my knowledge and have a positive impact on our world.

- Proficient in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Python.
- 6 years' industry experience working as part of a team on creative projects for a variety of clients across construction, education, and healthcare.
- 3 years' industry experience designing construction site graphics while overseeing art department and training junior staff members.
- Extensive knowledge of Adobe Illustrator and After Effects.

Technologies:

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- Python
- Adobe After Effects, Illustrator, Adobe XD, Premier Pro, Photoshop

Frameworks:

- Django
- Bootstrap

Version Control:

- Git
- GitHub

Full UK driving licence.

Fluent in English and Swedish.

Education

Code Institute: 08/2023 – 12/2023 Full-Stack Developer bootcamp

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Bootstrap, and Django.
- 16 week full-stack developer course.
- Building solid foundations of modern coding practices through online tutoring and self-guided study.
- Creating brief led web applications with a team during 3-day hackathons.
- Utilising the agile methodology to ensure project is created in a pragmatic manner.
- Utilising UX fundamentals to design and build professional, intuitive web applications.

University of South Wales: 2012 – 2015

BA Hons 2D Animation

- Developing strong understanding of design principles.
- Developing animation, illustration, and graphic design skills with traditional and digital methods.

Work Experience

Freelance

Junior Developer / Animator / Designer: 2023 - Present

- Developing and maintaining relationships with new clients to create a comfortable working environment.
- Liaising with clients to develop clear user stories and acceptance criteria.
- Creating designs based on brand and brief guidelines. Ensuring client can discuss, review, and amend.
- Creating manageable tasks with the use of a digital kanban board. Guaranteeing that features are developed and reviewed in a pragmatic manner.
- Reflecting on completed projects with clients to figure out what worked, what didn't, and why.
- Researching new skills and technologies within design and software development building upon my coding foundations.

Full-time

Tree Top Films

Animator / Designer: 2017 - 2023

- Collaborating with clients and Tree Top's design team to research, develop strategy, and project deliverables.
- Overseeing and developing concepts and final design assets with wider team. Consulting with clients to discuss, review, and amend.
- Collating feedback for the team and ensuring all assets are delivered at a high standard.
- Ensuring that each stage of a project runs smoothly sticking to budgets and project timelines.
- Organising and creating project archive system.
- Continuing to learn and develop skills with up-to-date techniques and software.
- Evaluating projects and discussing outtakes with client to improve future projects and develop the creative team.

Scafftag

Art Department Supervisor / Graphic Designer

(Tree Top Films were contracted as Scafftag's Art Department): 2017 - 2020

- Collaborating with sales and customer service team to develop core requirements for designs to create functional and legible construction site graphics.
- Consulting with client throughout project to ensure final deliverables are created according to customer's requirements.
- Organising file structure and keeping track of project designs with Excel.
- Training and overseeing junior members of staff to follow correct procedure and adhere to design principles.

Freelance

Limbic Cinema Animator: 2022

- Collaborating with Limbic Cinema's team to understand project requirements and establish deadlines.
- Research, edit, and animate imagery & graphics with After Effects.
- Continuously managing timeline and ensuring deadlines are met.
- Allowing time for review and amendments.
- Animating, exporting, and delivering animation.

Gambit

Designer / Animator: 2022

- Liaising with client to establish project deliverables.
- Creating storyboard, relevant graphics, and sourcing logos to feature in the animation.
- Allowing time for review and amendments.
- Animating, exporting, and delivering animation.

Vitol

Animator / Designer: 2021

- Consulting with the client to develop project plan and final deliverables.
- Researching and understanding brand guidelines to ensure assets are created to match existing brand style.
- Collaborating with other freelancers to design initial concepts and final designs for scene and characters.
- Rigging characters.
- Animating scenes and characters.
- Managing other freelancers work to ensure consistency in animation style.
- Ensuring that each stage of the project was reviewed and approved.